Mauro Lavigna

Software Engineer

mauro.lavigna@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mauro-lavigna/

Summary

Seasoned Software Engineer with 8+ years of experience and knowledge on web-based and standalone applications. Professional, flexible, creative, and service-oriented. Offering a unique combination of creativity for problem solving and analytical skill with the ability to assess both vantage points to create cost-effective solutions for internal and external clients.

Experience

Engineering Team Lead at InTouch Health

Sept 2017 – Present

Managing a small team of software engineers with responsibilities over several full-stack projects, technologies and designs. Developing an Identity Provider server, an Authorization Provider, and a set of web APIs for a device's Fleet Monitoring System, all hosted with high-availability on AWS.

Software Engineer at InTouch Health

Feb 2014 – Aug 2017 (3 years 7 months)

As a member of a scrum team designing, developing and maintaining a collection of systems consisting of a set of web applications, Windows services, and REST web services to monitor and administer the company's telehealth devices fleet.

Software QA Engineer at InTouch Health

Oct 2011 – Jan 2014 (2 years 4 months)

Performing tests on web-based applications and validating their functionality before they reached the customers. Proposing and working on the first automation project for some of the extensive suite of test cases.

IT, Technical Services at InTouch Health

Dec 2009 – Sep 2011 (1 year 10 months)

As a part of the Technical Support team assisting physicians and solving all kinds of problems over the phone. Additionally, performing server's maintenance tasks, creating automated scripts for recurrent tasks, and training new members of the team on new systems or procedures.

Projects

Identity Provider

Aims to unify the company's authentication and user identity data with a set of web APIs and a front-end website, that authenticates users and systems by means of security tokens.

- Implemented from scratch using the latest ASP.NET Core using the OpenID Connect Certified IdentityServer4 framework.
- Achieved a high-availability architecture through AWS technologies: Elastic Beanstalk, RDS, Application ELB for multiple running instances and with MultiAZ, Rolling updates, Blue-Green deployments and a fall-back region
- On-boarded several clients from the company including SPAs, WebApps, and protected API resources
- Added SAML support and integrated with external federation services, such as customers' ADFS identity servers
- Worked on the continuous integration and continuous deployment pipeline.

Fleet Monitoring System

Web-based pages and APIs companion to the Remote Presence telehealth devices, custom-designed to support an administrator's fleet management and monitoring workflow.

- Implementing several new features for the system, including communication with Kafka servers, AuthO, a synchronization module with SIP servers, front-end pages on ASP.NET + HTML5, scheduled tasks, REST web services and Windows Services.
- Redesigning the database model, and refactoring code to modern standards of C# and .NET 4.5.6.
- Migration of all our servers to Windows Server 2016 and cloud Amazon Web Services.
- Migration of the code base from centralized Perforce VCS to GitHub.
- Improving the overall usability of the system.
- Finding and fixing bugs for different browsers and platforms.
- Writing unit tests and integration tests.
- Writing Requirement Specification and Verification Test Plans for the whole system.
- Extreme Programming techniques used on a day-to-day basis.

Independent Projects

■ I try to continuously improve my skills reading books, doing courses and exploring new technologies. You may check some of these out on my GitHub Page https://github.com/regul4rj0hn

Skills & Expertise

Practical Knowledge

C# – JavaScript – SQL

Previous Experience

ReactJS - NodeJS - VueJS

Tools & Expertise

Amazon Web Services – Git – ASP.NET – MVC – Docker – Entity Framework – Serilog – Jenkins – Apache Kafka – UML – Linux (Arch, Debian) – Remote Support – Agile Methodologies

Education

Universidad Nacional del Sur

Engineer, Computer Systems, 2006 - 2011

62% Completed, relevant courses included:

(7526) Computer Architecture - (5744) Computer Organization - (7655) Data Structures - (7642) Database Systems - (2907) Digital Techniques - (5941) Distributed Systems - (7791) Formal Languages and Automata - (7703) Human-Computer Interaction - (5786) Networking and Teleprocessing - (7713) Object Oriented Programming - (5949) Operative Systems - (5793) Problem Solving and Algorithms - (7951) Programming Technologies - (7820) Statistical Models for Computer Science - (7534) Systems Audit - (7901) Systems Security - (7949) Theory of Computation - (5704) Logic for Computer Science

Colegio Claret

BA, Economics and Management of Organizations, 2000 - 2005

Languages

English (Native or bilingual proficiency)

Spanish (Native or bilingual proficiency)

German (Elementary proficiency)

Recommendations

Jonathan Simpson: Co-worker since 2014. Email: simpson27@gmail.com Joaquin Espinosa: Co-worker since 2012. Email: joacoespinosa@gmail.com

For managers and other recommendations please refer to my LinkedIn profile:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mauro-lavigna/